Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Unterstützen Sie den Administrator! Schauen Sie auf kissasia.cam oder kisskh.org vorbei.
SHOGI ASSOCIATION HEADQUARTERS
HAUPTSITZ DER SHOGI-VERBAND
Are you authorized?
Sind Sie dazu berechtigt?
I'm a kishi.
Ich bin ein Kishi.
-Sorry. -Apologies.
-Entschuldigung. -Ich bitte um Entschuldigung.
Well, a former kishi.
Nun ja, ein ehemaliger Kishi.
Long time no see, everyone.
Lange nicht gesehen, alle zusammen.
Seigo Todou here.
Seigo Todou hier.
I'm here today to speak with Shoichi Yuuki.
Ich bin heute hier, um mit Shoichi Yuuki zu sprechen.
The new chairman of the Japan Shogi Association.
Der neue Vorsitzende des Japanischen Shogi-Verbandes.
Is he here?
Ist er hier?
I assume you've all heard of Asuka Kunimi.
Ich nehme an, ihr habt alle schon mal von Asuka Kunimi gehört.
She's been winning matches against kishi,
Sie hat Kämpfe gegen Kishi gewonnen.
and defeated Hayami joryu 3-dan, in the last tournament.
und besiegte Hayami Joryu 3-Dan im letzten Turnier.
She only needs another win to qualify for the kishi admission test.
Sie braucht nur noch einen Sieg, um sich für die Kishi-Aufnahmeprüfung zu qualifizieren.
-Call security. -Okay.
-Rufen Sie den Sicherheitsdienst. -Okay.
I'm not here to punch Yuuki again.
Ich bin nicht hier, um Yuuki noch einmal zu schlagen.
Mr. Todou, this is not appropriate.
Herr Todou, das ist nicht angemessen.
I just came to ask why Asuka Kunimi isn't allowed into tournaments.
Ich wollte nur fragen, warum Asuka Kunimi nicht zu Turnieren zugelassen wird.
So you know, huh?
Du weißt schon, was?
Then tell me.
Dann erzähl es mir.
Hey! Anyone care to explain?
Hey! Kann das jemand erklären?
That's him.
Das ist er.
Come with us.
Komm mit uns.
Hands off! I won't do anything.
Finger weg! Ich werde nichts tun.
Calm down!
Beruhige dich!
Get off me! I'm calm!
Lass mich los! Ich bin ruhig!
Being violent again?
Schon wieder gewalttätig?
Let Asuka Kunimi compete!
Lasst Asuka Kunimi antreten!
Please leave.
Bitte gehen Sie.
Are you all her puppets, or what?
Seid ihr alle ihre Marionetten oder was?
Why're you interfering when the very first female kishi is emerging?
Warum greifst du ein, wo doch gerade das allererste weibliche Kishi schlüpft?
Don't you have any pride as a shogi player?
Hast du denn gar keinen Stolz als Shogi-Spieler?
I'm just playing the best move.
Ich spiele einfach den besten Zug.
And I'm no longer a shogi player.
Und ich spiele kein Shogi mehr.
Take him out.
Bringt ihn raus.
Yes, ma'am.
Ja, Ma'am.
-Come on. -This way.
-Komm schon. -Hier entlang.
Don't think you can get away.
Glaub ja nicht, dass du damit durchkommst.
Asuka Kunimi hasn't resigned yet.
Asuka Kunimi ist noch nicht zurückgetreten.
You haven't defeated her yet!
Du hast sie noch nicht besiegt!
Get your hands off me!
Lass die Finger von mir!
Are you okay like that?
Ist das für dich in Ordnung?
Sure. I could put them closer so they'd topple cleaner--
Klar. Ich könnte sie näher zusammenstellen, damit sie sauberer umkippen.
I'm not talking about the dominoes.
Ich spreche nicht von Dominosteinen.
What?
Was?
You've been banned from tournaments, right?
Du wurdest von Turnieren ausgeschlossen, richtig?
Aren't you anxious?
Bist du nicht ängstlich?
Well yeah, but…
Ja, aber…
It's not like I can do anything to change the situation.
Es ist nicht so, als könnte ich irgendetwas tun, um die Situation zu ändern.
Yes, that's true.
Ja, das stimmt.
Mr. Todou's helping me get permission to enter the tournaments, so…
Herr Todou hilft mir dabei, die Erlaubnis zur Teilnahme an den Turnieren zu erhalten, also…
Right.
Rechts.
KING
KÖNIG
I will beat him.
Ich werde ihn besiegen.
Hey, let's go.
Hey, los geht's.
Aw, man.
Ach, Mann.
To where? What about the association?
Wohin? Und wie steht es mit dem Zusammenhang?
They're a bunch of idiots. Totally useless.
Das sind alles Idioten. Absolut nutzlos.
But that helped me figure it out.
Aber das hat mir geholfen, es herauszufinden.
Use your rook in a cross.
Setze deinen Turm im Kreuz ein.
If the vertical is blocked, go horizontal.
Wenn die Vertikale blockiert ist, gehen Sie horizontal vor.
Let's go play some shogi.
Lasst uns Shogi spielen.
Hey, where are you going?
Hey, wo gehst du hin?
To play the next move.
Den nächsten Zug ausführen.
That went quite smoothly.
Das verlief reibungslos.
Yes, very good.
Ja, sehr gut.
Thank you for your hard work.
Vielen Dank für Ihre harte Arbeit.
Thank you.
Danke schön.
-Shall we have lunch? -Thank you.
-Sollen wir zu Mittag essen? -Danke.
Yes, let's go.
Ja, los geht's.
Thank you, sir.
Danke, Sir.
Oh, hi. Got a game today?
Oh, hallo. Hast du heute ein Spiel?
Yes. I'm on lunch break.
Ja. Ich habe Mittagspause.
Well, good luck.
Na dann, viel Glück.
Perfect timing.
Perfektes Timing.
You will be the director of the tournament operations.
Sie werden die Leitung des Turnierbetriebs übernehmen.
APPOINTMENT
TERMIN
What?
Was?
I'd like you to support the association as a director from now on.
Ich möchte Sie bitten, den Verein ab sofort als Vorstandsmitglied zu unterstützen.
Are you serious, Mom?
Meinst du das ernst, Mama?
Here, you will call me "Executive Director".
Hier nennen Sie mich „Geschäftsführer“.
Well…
Also…
I'm counting on you, Director Yuuki.
Ich zähle auf Sie, Direktor Yuuki.
TESSAI ANDO
TESSAI ANDO
It's been so long, Master Tessai.
Es ist schon so lange her, Meister Tessai.
I apologize for all the trouble back then.
Ich entschuldige mich für alle Unannehmlichkeiten von damals.
What are you doing here? You left shogi.
Was machst du hier? Du hast Shogi verlassen.
This is Asuka Kunimi.
Das ist Asuka Kunimi.
Shoichi Yuuki's daughter.
Shoichi Yuukis Tochter.
She's trying to become a kishi.
Sie versucht, eine Kishi zu werden.
But the association is interfering, banning her from tournaments.
Doch der Verband mischt sich ein und verbietet ihr die Teilnahme an Turnieren.
Master Tessai, could you please help--
Meister Tessai, könnten Sie bitte helfen?
Not my business.
Geht mich nichts an.
Leave.
Verlassen.
We've been long over.
Das ist schon lange vorbei.
Besides, I'm not the chairman now.
Außerdem bin ich jetzt nicht mehr der Vorsitzende.
Master Tessai!
Meister Tessai!
She's strong.
Sie ist stark.
Not like other ordinary kishi.
Nicht wie andere gewöhnliche Kishi.
She might even beat you.
Sie könnte dich sogar schlagen.
What are you saying?
Was sagst du?
Wouldn’t you like to see the very first female kishi?
Würdest du nicht gerne die allererste weibliche Kishi sehen ?
Asuka Kunimi has the potential.
Asuka Kunimi hat das Potenzial.
The disciple you once failed to make a kishi is interfering.
Der Schüler, dem du einst nicht gelungen bist, ein Kishi zu machen, mischt sich ein.
Kaori Yuuki.
Kaori Yuuki.
Oh, right. I remember now…
Ach ja. Jetzt erinnere ich mich wieder…
You were good at mind games.
Du warst gut in Psychospielchen.
Play a game with me.
Spiel mit mir.
Beautiful sound.
Wunderschöner Klang.
Kaori Yuuki also used to make that sound when she played.
Auch Kaori Yuuki machte dieses Geräusch, wenn sie spielte.
That's a beautiful sound you made.
Das war ein wunderschöner Klang, den du da erzeugt hast.
Staying back to practice, Kaori?
Bleibst du zum Training zurück, Kaori?
Yes.
Ja.
Just don't push yourself too hard.
Überanstreng dich nicht.
Master.
Master.
Yes?
Ja?
Is it true that women can't become a kishi?
Stimmt es, dass Frauen keine Kishi werden können?
What?
Was?
Well no, that's not--
Nein, das ist nicht...
Is it true that women are weaker than men?
Stimmt es, dass Frauen schwächer sind als Männer?
I…
ICH…
I must become stronger, like my father.
Ich muss stärker werden, so wie mein Vater.
I'll become strong and leave the Shoreikai.
Ich werde stark werden und Shoreikai verlassen.
And I'll become a kishi.
Und ich werde ein Kishi.
But…
Aber…
If you focus only on which moves to make in the future,
Wenn Sie sich nur darauf konzentrieren, welche Schritte Sie in Zukunft unternehmen sollten,
you might have the rug pulled out from under you.
Es könnte passieren, dass Ihnen der Boden unter den Füßen weggezogen wird.
Have some.
Nimm dir welche.
I resign.
Ich trete zurück.
Thank you.
Danke schön.
Great, you're crying now.
Toll, jetzt weinst du auch noch.
That's why women are…
Deshalb sind Frauen…
Hi, Kaori. Tough day today, huh?
Hallo Kaori. War heute wohl ein anstrengender Tag, was?
But with your excellence, you would dominate as a joryu kishi.
Aber mit deiner Exzellenz würdest du als Joryu Kishi dominieren.
That'll be the best.
Das wäre am besten.
Spice up the shogi world.
Bringt Würze in die Shogi-Welt.
Become a joryu.
Werde ein Joryu.
See you.
Wir sehen uns.
-Hey, look. -Oh, what?
-Hey, schau mal. -Oh, was?
Whoa, hey.
Wow, hey.
-No way. -Seriously?
-Unmöglich. -Im Ernst?
Come on…
Aufleuchten…
You're kidding me.
Das ist doch nicht dein Ernst!
I resign.
Ich trete zurück.
That's how much pressure Kaori Yuuki put on herself.
So viel Druck machte sich Kaori Yuuki selbst.
Yet, she still couldn't make it.
Dennoch hat sie es nicht geschafft.
ROOK
TURM
You can tell how confident the move is
Man kann erkennen, wie selbstsicher der Schritt ist.
from the sound.
vom Klang her.
Want some?
Möchtest du welche?
No thanks.
Nein danke.
-Hey! -I don't mind at all.
-Hey! -Das macht mir überhaupt nichts aus.
Sorry about her.
Es tut mir leid für sie.
So…
Also…
Why do you want to become the first female kishi?
Warum möchtest du die erste weibliche Kishi werden ?
No woman has ever made it until now.
Bis jetzt hat es noch keine Frau geschafft.
It's a thorny path.
Es ist ein dorniger Weg.
And yet, you--
Und dennoch, du –
Are you already retired?
Sind Sie bereits im Ruhestand?
-What? -Hey!
-Was? -Hey!
That's right. I retired when I was 62.
Das stimmt. Ich bin mit 62 Jahren in Rente gegangen.
Sixty-two years old.
Zweiundsechzig Jahre alt.
But…
Aber…
you retired because you couldn't win anymore.
Du hast deine Karriere beendet , weil du nicht mehr gewinnen konntest.
Hey, idiot!
Hey, Idiot!
I'm so sorry.
Es tut mir so leid.
Oh, I mean,
Oh, ich meine,
it's just the same, isn't it?
Es ist doch genau dasselbe, nicht wahr?
Your question earlier.
Ihre Frage von vorhin.
What?
Was?
Age? Gender?
Alter? Geschlecht?
None of that matters when you sit at the board, does it?
Das alles spielt keine Rolle mehr, wenn man im Vorstand sitzt, nicht wahr?
Yes.
Ja.
It doesn't matter.
Das spielt keine Rolle.
I didn't ask the question in the right way.
Ich habe die Frage nicht richtig gestellt.
Why do you want to become a kishi?
Warum möchtest du ein Kishi werden?
To fight against this shitty world.
Um gegen diese beschissene Welt anzukämpfen.
Great sound.
Toller Klang.
I resign.
Ich trete zurück.
Don't ever change.
Verändere dich niemals.
Stay true to yourself.
Stay true to yourself.
TATSUYA YUUKI C-CLASS STANDINGS
TATSUYA YUUKI C-CLASS STANDINGS
Again…
Again…
I lost.
I lost.
Mom told me…
Mom told me…
to be the association's director.
to be the association's director.
Apparently…
Apparently…
the Yuuki family doesn't need a joryu kishi
the Yuuki family doesn't need a joryu kishi
or a C-Class player.
or a C-Class player.
PRIVATE MATCH ROOM
PRIVATE MATCH ROOM
SINGLE-MINDED DEDICATION
SINGLE-MINDED DEDICATION
NOTICE OF WITHDRAWAL
NOTICE OF WITHDRAWAL
I didn't realize. Please excuse me for interrupting you.
I didn't realize. Please excuse me for interrupting you.
Your father…
Your father…
took very good care of me.
took very good care of me.
I'm so honored you remember him.
I'm so honored you remember him.
Good luck.
Good luck.
I'm…
I'm…
I'm quitting shogi.
I'm quitting shogi.
I followed his words here.
I followed his words here.
I tried to be strong.
I tried to be strong.
I solely focused on shogi…
I solely focused on shogi…
leaving everything else behind.
leaving everything else behind.
What else now?
What else now?
I have…
I have…
nothing else to leave behind.
nothing else to leave behind.
What could I have done…
What could I have done…
to be strong like you?
to be strong like you?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm just weak. That's all.
I'm just weak. That's all.
I don't know…
I don't know…
if you're really weak.
if you're really weak.
But,
But,
I know that…
I know that…
I am weak too.
I am weak too.
I've been drawing strength from Master Yuuki's words.
I've been drawing strength from Master Yuuki's words.
That's why I'm in this room,
That's why I'm in this room,
facing the board for hours.
facing the board for hours.
In the eyes of people,
In the eyes of people,
I was a villain.
I was a villain.
A monster.
A monster.
Heartless.
Heartless.
After I found myself at my lowest point…
After I found myself at my lowest point…
I am finally…
I am finally…
getting close.
getting close.
I'm finally about to grasp my own style in shogi.
I'm finally about to grasp my own style in shogi.
It is in my reach now.
It is in my reach now.
I don't want to lose it again.
I don't want to lose it again.
I still have…
I still have…
a long way to go.
a long way to go.
You're allowed into tournaments now!
You're allowed into tournaments now!
I knew Master Tessai could make it happen.
I knew Master Tessai could make it happen.
That's amazing!
That's amazing!
List of participants.
List of participants.
-Seigo. Great job! -Right.
-Seigo. Great job! -Right.
My plan worked.
My plan worked.
TOFU NEWSPAPER CUP FUSO TOURNAMENT
TOFU NEWSPAPER CUP FUSO TOURNAMENT
WAITING ROOM
WAITING ROOM
Why are you in the tournament?
Why are you in the tournament?
I'm not your puppet.
I'm not your puppet.
I live my life on my own terms.
I live my life on my own terms.
If you lose…
If you lose…
you know what happens.
you know what happens.
I know.
I know.
Executive Yuuki.
Executive Yuuki.
-Chairman. Pleasure to see you. -Hi there.
-Chairman. Pleasure to see you. -Hi there.
Master Tessai told me about her.
Master Tessai told me about her.
Asuka Kunimi, amateur.
Asuka Kunimi, amateur.
Sounds like she's in the spotlight.
Sounds like she's in the spotlight.
Yes, she is.
Yes, she is.
If she wins, she can take the kishi admission test?
If she wins, she can take the kishi admission test?
Yes.
Ja.
It is time for the first round.
It is time for the first round.
Asuka Kunimi, amateur versus Tatsuya Yuuki, 6-dan.
Asuka Kunimi, amateur versus Tatsuya Yuuki, 6-dan.
Please begin.
Please begin.
Let's have a good game.
Let's have a good game.
Yes.
Ja.
Doesn't look like he's going to make it easy.
Doesn't look like he's going to make it easy.
Really?
Really?
Damn.
Damn.
Hey, why is he so strong?
Hey, why is he so strong?
The opponents she's had so far knew nothing about her.
The opponents she's had so far knew nothing about her.
You can take measures if you know the opponent's habits and favorite moves.
You can take measures if you know the opponent's habits and favorite moves.
That boy must've studied Asuka's style closely.
That boy must've studied Asuka's style closely.
That's no good!
That's no good!
Kunimi amateur, ten minutes remaining.
Kunimi amateur, ten minutes remaining.
That's a nasty setup.
That's a nasty setup.
He's staying out of her territory, while slowly dismantling her plans.
He's staying out of her territory, while slowly dismantling her plans.
This is bad.
This is bad.
She's losing time.
She's losing time.
Well, what are you going to do?
Well, what are you going to do?
That guy. Is he doing that on purpose?
That guy. Is he doing that on purpose?
Harassing her nonstop.
Harassing her nonstop.
What a jerk.
What a jerk.
Kunimi amateur, five minutes remaining.
Kunimi amateur, five minutes remaining.
I got it.
I got it.
Nice.
Nice.
Great sound.
Great sound.
I resign.
I resign.
After 145 moves, Asuka Kunimi amateur, wins.
Nach 145 Zügen gewinnt die Amateurin Asuka Kunimi.
Yes!
Ja!
Good!
Gut!
Quite the glutton she is.
Sie ist eine richtige Vielfraß.
Don't you think so?
Findest du nicht auch?
Master.
Master.
I'm not your apprentice anymore,
Ich bin nicht mehr dein Lehrling.
yet you are still trying to teach me something.
Und doch versuchst du mir immer noch etwas beizubringen.
Too bad.
Schade.
I still won't be eating daifuku.
Ich werde trotzdem kein Daifuku essen.
We're preparing for the next match.
Wir bereiten uns auf das nächste Spiel vor.
Your style was unlike anyone I've ever played with.
Dein Spielstil war einzigartig, anders als bei allen anderen Spielern, mit denen ich je gespielt habe.
It was…
Es war…
interesting.
interessant.
Still want to be a kishi?
Willst du immer noch ein Kishi sein?
You'll have to face men who are like monsters.
Du wirst Männern gegenüberstehen , die wie Monster sind.
You won't make it.
Du schaffst es nicht.
Oh, I know.
Oh, ich weiß.
A "wall that women can't overcome."
Eine „Mauer, die Frauen nicht überwinden können“.
And…
Und…
Dad is at the top.
Papa steht an der Spitze.
So what?
Na und?
If it's too high to climb…
Wenn es zu hoch zum Klettern ist…
What, smash it?
Was, es zerschlagen?
No.
NEIN.
I'll use everyone as a stepping stone,
Ich werde jeden als Sprungbrett benutzen.
and rise above.
und sich darüber erheben.
Thanks.
Danke.
I'll be back.
Ich komme wieder.
Thank you so much. See you again.
Vielen Dank. Bis bald.
See you.
Wir sehen uns.
You're Seigo Todou, right?
Du bist Seigo Todou, oder?
Yes?
Ja?
Sorry to bother you.
Tut mir leid, Sie zu stören.
My name is Shibata.
Mein Name ist Shibata.
I write for the Weekly Bunka.
Ich schreibe für die Weekly Bunka.
What?
Was?
So, could I ask some questions about Asuka Kunimi?
Darf ich ein paar Fragen zu Asuka Kunimi stellen?
Do you recognize the person in this picture?
Erkennen Sie die Person auf diesem Bild?
Is everything written in this article true?
Stimmt alles, was in diesem Artikel steht?
EXPELLED KISHI ATTEMPTED MURDER?
VERSCHULDIGTER KISHI VERSUCHTE EINEN MORD?
PLANNED REVENGE ON SHOICHI YUUKI
Geplante Rache an Shoichi Yuuki
SCOOP! SECRET CHILD
Exklusiv! Geheimes Kind
It's the biggest scandal ever.
Das ist der größte Skandal aller Zeiten.
Why did you leak it?
Warum hast du es durchsickern lassen?
Because it's more fun that way.
Weil es so mehr Spaß macht.
It's blowing up.
Es explodiert.
If she wins three games, she'll be the very first female kishi.
Wenn sie drei Spiele gewinnt, wird sie die allererste weibliche Kishi sein.
Win all the games.
Gewinne alle Spiele.
That's the fastest way to get to Shoichi Yuuki.
Das ist der schnellste Weg, um zu Shoichi Yuuki zu gelangen.
Stop it!
Hör auf damit!
Apparently, people call me a terrorist now.
Offenbar bezeichnen mich die Leute jetzt als Terroristen.
It sucks. It's your fault.
Das ist Mist. Das ist deine Schuld.
Kunimi amateur, lost two in a row.
Kunimi, Amateur, verlor zwei Spiele in Folge.
Another loss, and she'll be disqualified.
Bei einer weiteren Niederlage wird sie disqualifiziert.
I'm sorry.
Es tut mir Leid.
Subtitle translation by: Kana S.
Untertitelübersetzung von: Kana S.